Portfolio GitHub in LinkedIn

82 Plymouth Avenue, Maplewood, NJ 07040 • mark@alienresident.net • 347 228 3696

Summarv

I am a User Experience Designer with over eighteen years in interactive media. My career spans the breadth of digital production, from production art to web design and front-end development. As a User Experience Designer, my in-depth understanding of the design process allows me to meet user goals while balancing aesthetics and technical constraints.

UX/UI Skills

- · Usability Testing, User Interviews, and Personas
- Sketching, Storyboarding, and Paper Prototyping
- · Wireframing, Card Sorting, and High-fidelity Prototyping
- · Markup (HTML) and Styling (CSS)
- · Visual Design, Style Guides, and Style Tiles
- · Typography and Graphic Production

Technical Skills

- · Sketch, Photoshop, OmniGraffle, Illustrator, Principle, Flash
- . HTML, CSS, Sass & Compass, Javascript & jQuery, Grunt & Gulp
- · Git & SVN, PHP, MySQL, Drupal

Professional Experience

KBS (kirshenbaum bond senecal)

March 2015-present

Associate Director, User Experience

KBS (kirshenbaum bond senecal) November 2016-present

- · Create a design system, user flows, and a prototype for Stanley Black & Decker's Lista product configurator
- · Design a skills matrix for the UX team to visualize strengths and gaps within the team. The skills matrix helps with allocations, skills training, and career development.
- · Create a Sketch and InVision based workflow to streamline work between departments; Wireframes are created by UX designers, visualized by UI designers, and then prepared for handoff to developers

Senior User Experience Designer

Spies & Assassins | KBS (kirshenbaum bond senecal) March 2015-November 2015

- Create a modular design system, wireframes, user flows, and prototypes for the responsive redesign of the BMW USA website
- Create wireframes, user flows, and prototypes for the redesign of the My BMW website
- Conduct user interviews and create content types and wireframes for the Hershey's digital marketing learning site

New York University

October 2008-March 2015

User Experience Specialist

Digital Communications Group, Information Technology Services August 2014-March 2015

- · Create a new responsive user interface for Sakai, an Open Source Learning Management System
- · Commit back the user experience work from NYU Classes to Sakai
- Design a new user interface for NYU's Email Direct a bulk email communication tool for NYU administrators

User Experience Designer

Academic Technology Services, Information Technology Services October 2011-August 2014

- Design a new user interface for NYU Classes the Learning Management System (LMS) based on extensive usability testing
- Create a 'Mobile First' prototype for our redesign of MediaCommons a digital network for professors and post-graduate students of film and media studies

Interactive Designer and Developer

Faculty Technology Services, Information Technology Services October 2008-October 2011

- Design and develop MediaCommons a digital network for professors and post-graduate students — using Drupal
- · Establish a distinctive look and feel for the MediaCommons network and it's project sites
- Design and develop book and photo viewing websites, and streaming audio and video for the NYU Libraries' special digital collections

Columbia University August 2001-September 2008

Senior Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures (a small 'digital agency' within Columbia University)

May 2005-September 2008

- · Create educational course content and departmental websites for Columbia University and affiliated non-profits
- · Design and develop websites using open source content management systems and static html

Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures August 2001-May 2005

- · Work with Columbia Faculty to design and develop interactive e-seminars and courses
- Design and develop interactive maps, audio slideshows, podcasts, and basic video production and post-production for streaming video and DVD

Scholastic

January 2000-May 2001

Web Designer

e-Scholastic

- · Design educational, commercial, and promotional websites for Scholastic
- · Design daily site graphics, flash based interactive quizzes and educational activities

Education

1999-2007 Ph.D. Media & Communication, European Graduate School, Saas-Fee, Switzerland

1998-2001 Certificate in Film Production, The New School, New York, NY

1995–1996 M.Phil. Medieval History, Trinity College, Dublin University, Ireland

1991-1994 B.A. History and Philosophy, University College Dublin, Ireland

Additional Information

Teaching

The New School, Fall 2004–Spring 2008 Adjunct faculty member, *Media Studies*

· Courses: Foundations of Media Design and Digital Video Effects

Columbia University, Summer 2005–Summer 2008 Instructor, *High School Program*

· Course: Digital Filmmaking

Organizations

- Co-Founder: NYU UX Group & NYU Web Designers and Developers Group
- Co-Organizer: DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10 NYC Drupal Users Group
- Member: IxDA NYC UXPA Gotham Sass Meetup NYC Drupal Users Group Agile Experience Design Meetup • Type Directors Club

Selected Presentations, Event Organization, and Trainings

Presentations

- Beyond Putting Lipstick on the Pig at EdUl 2014 30th September, 2014
- Sakai: Meet MORPHEUS at Open Apereo 2014 2nd June, 2014
- Rapid Protoyping Techniques at TorchTech: UX Networking Breakfast 23rd April, 2014
- Fixing Broken User Experience at NYU ITS All Hands Meeting 21st September, 2012
- MediaCommons 2.0 at Digital Library Federation Forum 5th May, 2009

Event Organization

- UX Networking Breakfast Co-Organizer TorchTech & NYU UX group 23rd April, 2014
- UX @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 14th November, 2013
- Usability @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 11th December, 2012
- DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10 Co-Organizer & Designer NYC Drupal Users Group June & December 2011

Trainings

- Design Teams Are a Design Exercise: How to Build, Inspire and Keep Design Teams (Happy) with Alberta Soranzo & Martina Hodges-Schell, Interaction 17 — February 2017
- Leading Creative Ideation with Christian Linsey & Jen Zhao, Cooper U May 2016
- Design Leadership with Teresa Brazen & Lane Halley, Cooper U August 2015
- Scaling User Interfaces with Amy Schade, Nielsen Norman Group August 2014
- UX Leadership with Kim Goodwin, Rosenfeld Media October 2012
- Do It Yourself Usability Testing with Steve Krug, Rosenfeld Media May 2012
- Sketching Interfaces with Jason Mesut & Sam Smith, Interaction 12 February 2012
- Mobile Prototyping Essentials with Rachel Hinman, Interaction 12 February 2012